We use pie and bar charts to visualize categorical data.
我们使用饼图和柱状图来可视化分类数据
If we have a list of numerical data,
如果我们拥有值数据列表
such as the list of stock prices over time,
例如一段时间内的股价列表
a line chart gives us a better picture of the data set.
那么折线图可以更好地展示数据集
Here's a table of data I downloaded from a financial website,
这是我从金融网站上下载的数据表格
listing prices for AAPL stock.
即 AAPL 股票的市价
It has columns for date, open,
它有日期 开盘价
high, low, close, and volume.
最高价、最低价、收盘价和成交量列
I want to select the date column and the close column
我想选择日期列和收盘价列
then go to the insert menu and select a line chart.
然后转到插入菜单并选择折线图
I can move the chart to its own sheet to see the detail better.
我可以将图表单独放入一个工作表中 这样更容易看清细节部分
The chart is a little plain,
这个图表比较普通
but there are several quick fixes in the chart design menu.
可以在图表设计菜单中快速改进一下
I'll choose one and change the title to AAPL Stock Price.
我将选择一个 并将标题改为 AAPL Stock Price
That was pretty easy.
很简单
The horizontal axis shows the dates,
横轴显示的是日期
and the vertical axis shows dollar values.
纵轴显示的是美元值
Now I can see, at a glance,
现在可以快速看出
that over the past year the stock has gone up with a little hiccup about a month ago.
在过去一年内 股价一直在上涨 只是上个月波动了下
If I have more than one column of data for the same dates,
如果同一日期有多列数据
I can show lines for each on the same chart.
我可以在同一图表上为每列显示一条直线
I'll use the same data set,
我将使用相同的数据集
but I'll select the date plus the high and low values for AAPL stock.
但是我将选择 AAPL Stock 的最高价和最低价
Since the high and low aren't all that far apart,
因为最高价和最低价相差并不大
I'll also change the range for the dollar amount on the left to start at 100.
我将左侧的美元值范围改为从 100 开始
Select the vertical axis,
选择纵轴
right click, and format axis.
右击并设定坐标轴格式
You can see both the high and low value lines now and see the spreads between them.
现在可以看到最高价和最低价折线 并可以看到二者之间的差别
There are a lot of ways to change the look of the same line chart by altering the layout.
有很多更改折线图外观的方法 可以修改布局
I could also try to plot two different variables for AAPL stock without dates at all,
我还可以不使用日期 绘制出 AAPL 股票的两个不同变量
such as the closing price and volume.
例如收盘价和成交量
When I choose the scatterplot,
当我选择散点图时
I get a graph with the closing price on
形成的图表是收盘价位于横轴上
the horizontal axis and the volume of trade that day on the vertical axis.
当天的成交量位于纵轴上
I can see that the prices seem to cluster in a couple of areas and that they have about
可以看出价格似乎都聚集在几个区域
the same volume generally though there are some high volume days at the lower price.
基本上成交量一样 虽然在一些较低价时对应高成交量